Office of Special Events and University Ceremonies records, 1967-2010, bulk 1993-2007 UA.03.04.0001
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Office of Special Events and University Ceremonies records
1967-2010, bulk 1993-2007
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Duke University. Office of Special Events and University Ceremonies
UA.03.04.0001
24 Linear Feet
The Office of Special Events and University Ceremonies was formed in 1983 to handle the planning of campus-wide events. The Office of Special Events and University Ceremonies records includes files related to the organization of events and ceremonies such as Commencement, Baccalaureate services, Founders' Day celebrations, Board of Trustees dinners, awards banquets, special guests at football and basketball games, and many others.
Historical note
The Office of Special Events and University Ceremonies was formed in 1983 to handle the planning of campus-wide events. Closely involved with the University Marshal, this office coordinates venues, food, parking, guest lists, invitations, and other logistics related to the planning and execution of large events and ceremonies including commencement exercises, baccalaureate services, Board of Trustee dinners, special award ceremonies, faculty events, and special guest attendance at sporting events on campus. Originally called the Office of Special Events when it was formed in 1983, Patricia Keller was Director until 1988; Lori Arthur was Director from 1988-19992; Virginia Shannon was Director from 1992-1994, and Terry Chambliss has been Director since 1994. Prior to the formation of this as a distinct office, event planning activities were conducted by assistants in the Office of the Secretary.
Collection Overview
The Office of Special Events and University Ceremonies records includes files related to the organization of events and ceremonies such as Commencement, Baccalaureate services, Founders' Day celebrations, Board of Trustees dinners, awards banquets, special guests at football and basketball games, and many others. Files primarily consist of planning documents such as guest lists, invitations, schedules and agendas, menus, receipts and invoices, and some correspondence. The records also include some photographs, video and audio recordings of events, including the inauguration of Nannerl O. Keohane as President of the University in 1993, and several floppy disks.
The majority of the files were arranged chronologically, with files for individual events, although some dates are out of order; these are the Event files. Many of these files are related to sporting events, award dinners/luncheons, trustee events, faculty events, and events hosted by or involving the President of the University. Files from 2007-2007 and 2009-2010 have a different arrangment, very closely related to the files and arrangement of the University Marshal records, and include more correspondence and topical files related to commencement and founders' day; these are the Academic year files.
Also included are event binders, primarily related to football games and including guest lists and details of special guest attendance at football games. Additional materials include copies of printed invitations and announcements, and recordings of commencements, baccalaureate services, banquets, and the innauguration of President Nannerl Keohane.
Access Restrictions
For a period of twenty-five years from the origin of the material, permission in writing from the office of origin and the University Archivist is required for use of administrative records. After twenty-five years, records that have been processed may be consulted with the permission of the University Archivist.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48-hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Related Materials
University Marshal Records, Duke University Archives, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University.
Office of the University Secretary Records, Duke University Archives, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University.
Commencement Exercises Reference Collection, Duke University Archives, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University.
Football Records, Duke University Archives, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University.
Provenance
The Office of Special Events and University Ceremonies records were received by the University Archives as a transfer in November, 2014.
DVDs; Audiocassettes; Floppy disks; CD-ROMs; VHS; Special events -- Planning; Duke University. Board of Trustees; Duke University. Office of Special Events and University Ceremonies; Duke University -- Commencement ceremonies; Duke University -- Football -- History -- 20th century; Keohane, Nannerl O., 1940-
- Event files, 1982-2005
  - Event files, 1982, 1984-1985, 1988, 1990, 1993-1994 (Box 1)
  - Event files, 1994-1996 (Box 2)
  - Event files, 1995-1996 (Box 3)
  - Event files, 1996-1997 (Box 4)
  - Event files, 1997-1998 (Box 5)
  - Event files, 1998-2000 (Box 6)
  - Event files, 2000-2001 (Box 7)
  - Event files, 2001-2002 (Box 8)
  - Event files, 2002-2003 (Box 9)
  - Event files, 2003 (Box 10)
  - Event files, mixed dates 1995-2005 (Box 10)
  - Event files, mixed dates 1988-2004 (Box 11)
  - Emeriti luncheon, 2001-2002 (Box 11)
  - Event photographs, 1992, undated (Box 11)
  - Event binders, 1994-2002 (Box 14)
  - Event binders, 2002-2006 (Box 15)
- Academic year files, 2006-2007, 2009-2010
  - Academic year files, 2006-2007 (Box 12)
  - Academic year files, 2006-2007 (Box 13)
  - Academic year files, 2009-2010 (Box 13)
  - Academic year files, 2009-2010 (Box 14)
- Printed materials, 1967-2006
  - Baccalaureate Services programs, 1970-2006 (Box 15)
  - Commencement programs, 1967-2005 (Box 15)
  - Invitations and announcements (Box 16)
- Audio-visual materials, 1991-2006
  - Video recordings, 2004-2006 (Box 15)
  - Video recordings, 1991, 1993, 2001-2004 (Box 16)
  - Audio recordings, 1993, 1995, 2001 (Box 16)
  - DUKEbasics CD-ROM, 2003 (Box 15)